<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Yuki's Boredom</title><link href="https://yukiisbored.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://yukiisbored.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://yukiisbored.github.io/</id><updated>2017-08-19T21:00:00+07:00</updated><entry><title>How did I get here?</title><link href="https://yukiisbored.github.io/how-did-i-get-here.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-19T21:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2017-08-19T21:00:00+07:00</updated><author><name>Muhammad Kaisar Arkhan</name></author><id>tag:yukiisbored.github.io,2017-08-19:/how-did-i-get-here.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div id="preamble"&gt;
&lt;div class="sectionbody"&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s one of those question that I often ask myself personally, How did I get
here. How did I became a maintainer for two organizations, How did I get a
freelancing job for a startup in Germany, How did I win Google Code-In,
and Who am I before living …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="preamble"&gt;
&lt;div class="sectionbody"&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s one of those question that I often ask myself personally, How did I get
here. How did I became a maintainer for two organizations, How did I get a
freelancing job for a startup in Germany, How did I win Google Code-In,
and Who am I before living inside a text editor from the 70s?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, I can be really annoying and just say "I don&amp;#8217;t know". Because, I really
don&amp;#8217;t know. It&amp;#8217;s not an easy question and it&amp;#8217;s not the one where there&amp;#8217;s only
one answer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have to start somewhere I guess, so.. hmm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let me start by what makes me interested with Computers. Why am I wasting a
lot of time inside my home in a dark room with a keyboard and a screen to
fill the room.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was around 2006, my family just moved to a new home and after a while my dad
got home and he brought a bunch of boxes, it was a lot of boxes in various
sizes. My dad was assembling something, well I&amp;#8217;m not sure because most likely
I just sleep and gaze myself to the television.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next morning, I saw a blue table on top of it is a bulky box that looks like
a TV, a thing with a lot of buttons, small curvy thing with a ball inside of it,
and lasty a tower painted black with silver buttons that electrocutes me every
time I press it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, It&amp;#8217;s a computer, my dad introduced me to it shortly and my memories are
fuzzy so I&amp;#8217;m not sure what happened. After a while, I got hooked&amp;#8230; on games
that were installed. It ran Windows 98 Second Edition and the game that I always
play on it was Daytona USA, Virtual Cop, and Tarzan. I don&amp;#8217;t know the
specifications of the computer. Hell, I don&amp;#8217;t know what a processor is and a
common misconception is I called the tower the "CPU" which is well, wrong.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, after a while, I got it running Windows XP and we had to move to my
grandma&amp;#8217;s house because my parents wanted to renovate the house. During my stay
at my grandma&amp;#8217;s, my dad brought me to this place where they sell a lot of CDs.
Well, we grabbed a bunch of games and the store offered me some free software
because we bought a lot of things, sure I wanted it. To my surprise, my dad
specifically picked this one green CD titled "Mandriva 2006". I didn&amp;#8217;t know what
it was back then, on the back cover it has pictures of penguins and on the front
cover it has a picture of a penguin. I remember gazing on the cover during the
ride back home, I wonder what it was.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we got home, my dad installed it on my computer and introduced me to it. It
was there, KDE 3. I still remember the stuff that I like about it even to this
day I still remember how cool and customizable it is. The popular skeumorphism
look just was really appealing back then. I remember try and see what every
single button does. I even notice this thing called "root", when I asked my dad
what it is and what&amp;#8217;s with the background which is a tile of bombs, he replied
with "don&amp;#8217;t use it your computer will explode". Looking at back it, I think he
just want me to not break the system, but back then I was scared and kept myself
away from it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also remember trying out SUSE Linux (before it was called openSUSE) after my
dad introduced me to this magazine called "InfoLinux" and Ubuntu after the house
renovation is done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was an odd kid back then, I was still a cry-baby, I don&amp;#8217;t know how everything
worked back then, and I usually find myself interested in odd and unfamiliar
things, like computers. It wasn&amp;#8217;t a common thing in Indonesia back in the day,
unlike in western countries where it&amp;#8217;s normal for kids to use a computer and
use the Internet. It wasn&amp;#8217;t common back then, Internet was a thing for people
who have a lot of money and dial up was the choice for most people. I still
remember the advertisement for Telkom&amp;#8217;s old Dial-up service. I remember that
I was intrigued looking at ad where a telephone line is plugged into a laptop
and they have to dial this number. Well, I always wondered what the Internet is
back in the day. I remember my dad used to connect to the Internet with a some
sort of USB Modem. I don&amp;#8217;t know what it was, but I remember I found out it&amp;#8217;s a
USB Bluetooth and he probably connected it to his phone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;While writing this, I don&amp;#8217;t have a clear timeline of my life. I didn&amp;#8217;t bother
to write a diary back then. So stuff will most likely mixed up but I do have a
clear timeline on some memorable moments but I remember them not on age but on
what grade of school I&amp;#8217;m on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I was an odd kid back then, I remember on the third grade me with a
couple of friends sitting and talking to each other&amp;#8230; about how people kill
themselves at this building that we looked at. Yes, I find it to be an odd topic
as well and my parents would worried about me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;On my 8th birthday, my dad got me a new computer. An Intel Core 2 Duo machine
with a whopping 2GB of RAM and an NVIDIA GeForce. I was suprised and happy. I
remember my dad teased me about an Intel Core 2 Duo PC on Ramadhan. It had
Ubuntu installed, I think it was 6.04 and Windows XP. Also, my dad installed
Compiz. Which is this magical box of desktop effects. I remember playing with it
for a long time. Desktop cubes, wobbling windows, etc. Enabling and playing with
every single effect. It was fun.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a while, my dad got Internet installed. Sweet, I remember after installing
when testing the Internet, the guy opened YouTube and a Tom and Jerry video. I
was like what&amp;#8217;s this?. My mom was worried about it though because she thought it
may have porn on it. Well, I didn&amp;#8217;t listen because I was interested. I remember
she used to watch a lot of ghost videos but what I usually watch is a lot of
tech videos. Like people running old versions of Windows on computers or consoles
running Ubuntu or homebrew and a lot of stuff. I remember the notepad videos and
the infamous Trance - 009 Sound System Dreamscape. A lot of people got annoyed
with the sond, but I like it. Anyway, YouTube is also the reason why I got
interested in this the electronics genre of music. Back then, I remember listening
to Daft Punk. I remember while going back home from School, my friends were having
a quiz about music artists and I mentioned Daft Punk. They didn&amp;#8217;t know about it and
thought I was making stuff up. Well, I like Daft Punk a lot back then, even today I
still find their songs to be really good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I think I was at the 9th grade that I started playing with Visual Basic. I
remember that I had VB 6.0 back in the day, it was like 2006 but I&amp;#8217;m really not
sure when because I had Linux installed and I know I had Windows XP before and after
it, but really I&amp;#8217;m not sure. Anyway, I remember playing around with the program and
started doing some crappy Internet browser, a crappy "OS" which is really just a
shell. I still know it&amp;#8217;s "programming" but I didn&amp;#8217;t know how to program, what I did
is just placing buttons and other GUI components and played around with the
properties and I did some tutorials from YouTube videos. Most of the time I just
copy-paste code and see what it does. From there, like most people with old 80s
BASIC games book, I know a bit of Visual Basic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the 5th grade, my dad got me into a Java course at Nurul Fikri. More on that
later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another thing that I have problems with is telling stories parts of my life.
It&amp;#8217;s the feeling of I don&amp;#8217;t want to miss stuff but I have to or it&amp;#8217;ll be really
really long. I remember on a trip a teacher wanted me to tell the other students
on how I won GCI and it ended up being 30 mins long. Well, yeah. I&amp;#8217;m not a good
speaker without something like slides or notes to limit my scope. Anyway, on this
blog post I can have the audacity to list them all and make this long, but I don&amp;#8217;t
want to. Because it&amp;#8217;ll be days to write and will have more words than your usual
Russian novel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;More on Part 2(?). I don&amp;#8217;t know when that will happen because it&amp;#8217;s pretty rare for
me to have time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Thanks for reading this long post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content></entry><entry><title>Some stuff</title><link href="https://yukiisbored.github.io/some-stuff.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-29T23:33:00+07:00</published><updated>2017-04-29T23:33:00+07:00</updated><author><name>Muhammad Kaisar Arkhan</name></author><id>tag:yukiisbored.github.io,2017-04-29:/some-stuff.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div id="preamble"&gt;
&lt;div class="sectionbody"&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accepting something is hard. There&amp;#8217;s a lot of things that I said in the past and
regretting it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I used to hate Ruby because at first glance it&amp;#8217;s hard to read and confusing, I
remember having a pretty heated conversation with a friend about it …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="preamble"&gt;
&lt;div class="sectionbody"&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Accepting something is hard. There&amp;#8217;s a lot of things that I said in the past and
regretting it in the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I used to hate Ruby because at first glance it&amp;#8217;s hard to read and confusing, I
remember having a pretty heated conversation with a friend about it. Well, after
a few moments of actually learning Ruby, I fell in love with it and started
hating Python and became a Ruby fanboy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s common for me to immediately hating after becoming a fanboy or watching a
video on hating X. Yeah, I know it&amp;#8217;s pretty childish and I&amp;#8217;m trying to not do it.
It&amp;#8217;s pretty hard nowadays to build my own genuine opinions after seeing someone
else&amp;#8217;s opinions, especially the ones you trust.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;An old friend of mine told me on the last presidential election that I became an
immediate fanboy of the losing campaign. Well, yeah, that was on elementary
school. That&amp;#8217;s because my family supports the losing campaign and I follow tehm.
But, I noticed that I&amp;#8217;m doing the same nowadays, which I regret.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;On my last blog post, I wrote the fact that I hate competitive programming. Well,
I still don&amp;#8217;t like the idea of competitive programming, but the hate is getting
smaller after interacting with the mentors. I wrote "cancerous elitism" probably
because I was really pissed that this competition is taking my schedule a lot.
Anyway, I still don&amp;#8217;t like it and it should be considered as a not-so-needed
skill, because in practice stuff like what competitive programming is practicing
is really rare. Not a lot of people are writing their own sorting function, you
use what&amp;#8217;s inside your language&amp;#8217;s standard library. Not a lot of people are
writing their own OpenGL or software renderer, people use game engines or
libraries like SDL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think competitive programming shouldn&amp;#8217;t be prioritized as the competition for
measuring computer/programming skills. I remember one of the mentors talks about
his experience in collaborating with other people on a project and how it&amp;#8217;s
unpleasant. His problems were inconsistent code style, unreadable code, etc. Well,
that&amp;#8217;s one of the reasons why I think something like Google Code-in should be
prioritized over something like competitive programming. Why? Because in GCI
you contribute to actual free software projects and practice collaborating with
other people and collective work. You&amp;#8217;ll know how to contribute, how to work with
other people, and useful stuff that keeps the project going stable and maintainable
like Version control systems (ex. &lt;span class="monospaced"&gt;git&lt;/span&gt;), linters (ex.&lt;span class="monospaced"&gt;coala&lt;/span&gt;), static code analysis,
continous integration (ex. &lt;span class="monospaced"&gt;travis&lt;/span&gt;), documentation tools (ex. &lt;span class="monospaced"&gt;docutils&lt;/span&gt;), etc.
Not to mention, when you contribute to free software, you&amp;#8217;ll get criticsm from
other programmers. This criticsm is important to improve your skills and be a lot
better. So you won&amp;#8217;t be a turtle inside your shell and keep doing the same crap
forever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, someone called me the Indonesian version of Stallman because I prefer FLOSS
a lot and use it over nonfree software. Well, they&amp;#8217;re not wrong, but I&amp;#8217;m not &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt;
hardcore because I still rely on nonfree software/services like Telegram, Twitter,
Github, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got a coala.io email address which is sweet. It&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="mailto:yuki@coala.io"&gt;yuki@coala.io&lt;/a&gt; and I really
wanna use it more. For now, I&amp;#8217;m still using &lt;a href="mailto:yukinagato@protonmail.com"&gt;yukinagato@protonmail.com&lt;/a&gt; as my main
email. I&amp;#8217;m still waiting for IMAP support, etc. Most likely i&amp;#8217;ll just set it to
forward to my main email. Who knows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, you may notice a new look on my blog. Well, I really want an improved and
more readable look of it. At first, I wanna try make my own theme but I really
suck at front-end (I would never be as good as &lt;a href="https://github.com/hemangk"&gt;@hemangsk&lt;/a&gt;).
So, I ended up forking Pure theme and make some changes, like make the sidebar
to be sexy pink and change some other stuff like my waifu on the corner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, I can&amp;#8217;t come up with titles for my posts, because most of them are just
"updates" or something that I have in mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I dockerized &lt;a href="https://gitmate.io"&gt;GitMate&lt;/a&gt; and really like the result, there are
some bugs that I&amp;#8217;ll fix tomorrow or later. I&amp;#8217;m still pretty stressed with the
bugs that came up on production, which I hope we can find the source. We probably
need more eyeballs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;My birthday is coming up, but I won&amp;#8217;t be getting any presents because my Dad
already bought me a really awesome laptop. Which is okay. Another thing that I
wanna do after I&amp;#8217;m 17 is to create a National ID card and create a new bank
account so I can actually receive money from various freelancing work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m really grateful for everything that happened to me in this year. I won GCI
2016, working for FLOSS organizations, freelancing on various projects. I&amp;#8217;m really
lucky.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, after actually meeting with the other participants I noticed a lot of
interesting people. Since i&amp;#8217;m on the province level and everything is more
concetrated. I can talk with more people and meet them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wanna promote GCI to them at some time, probably when I lose on the province
level because I honestly doubt that I win. Some of the mentors has some hopes that
I win. But I honestly doubt that. If I do, I have no idea and very grateful to
Allah.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really wanna tell people and promote FOSS to local programmers especially the
ones who wanna be programmers because it&amp;#8217;s the most effective way to practice
and improve their skills. I&amp;#8217;m hoping more people will join Besut Kode 2017. I don&amp;#8217;t
know if I&amp;#8217;ll be a mentor again this year, so yeah.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m really grateful and really wanna thank Wikimedia Indonesia for doing programs
and initiatives like Besut Kode, WikiLatih, etc. They&amp;#8217;re really nice people and
are doing really awesome things. I wish more teachers, professors, people
contribute to Wikipedia Indonesia. You see, a lot of teachers don&amp;#8217;t like Wikipedia
because of it&amp;#8217;s "inaccurateness" and collective ways, I really want to tell them,
"If you know it&amp;#8217;s wrong, fix it". Because it&amp;#8217;s stupid to think something open and
collective will always be wrong even though there&amp;#8217;s a lot of people who verifies
changes and reverts vandalism.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m also really grateful to be a part of coala and FOSSASIA. They&amp;#8217;ve done a lot
for me, even if it&amp;#8217;s indirect. They gave me experiences in FOSS, System
Administration experiences, etc. I wish I took more photos when I visit FOSSASIA
2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, I noticed a lot of the competitive programming mentors haven&amp;#8217;t heard about
GSoC. Like seriously. They know Google Code Jam, but not GSoC. Well, I&amp;#8217;m hoping
to promote it to them at some point of time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Talking about GSoC, I&amp;#8217;m mentoring for coala this year. Which is awesome. I&amp;#8217;m
hoping I can be a student for GSoC in the future. If not, I&amp;#8217;ll probably join
Xorg&amp;#8217;s EVOC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;coala is considering doing it&amp;#8217;s own summer coding program. Which is awesome,
no idea if it&amp;#8217;ll be a thing or not though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, yeah, I kinda wanna do things for Xorg in the future. I just don&amp;#8217;t have the
time to learn the code base and more stuff about C and UNIX programming. I don&amp;#8217;t
know if I can, but I&amp;#8217;ll try.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another thing that I wanna do is more advanced stuff like Assembly/Low Level
programming. Just as a hobby. I don&amp;#8217;t know where should I start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, right now, I really want a new ergonomic keyboard because my current one
is start to become a pain. Sure it&amp;#8217;s not bad as the old one but it&amp;#8217;s starts to
become a pain. I&amp;#8217;m looking at the Microsoft Sculpt Keyboard and start saving
money for it. I don&amp;#8217;t know if my parents would buy it for me or not because it&amp;#8217;s
pretty expensive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also wanna continue my Linux primer book, I&amp;#8217;m hoping to that pretty soon,
because I wanna teach my friends the beauty of *nix operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, That&amp;#8217;s it for now. This damn AsciiDoc file is fucking 143 lines long.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks,
Muhammad Kaisar Arkhan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="opinions"></category><category term="stories"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello again</title><link href="https://yukiisbored.github.io/hello-again.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-13T20:34:00+07:00</published><updated>2017-04-15T20:29:00+07:00</updated><author><name>Muhammad Kaisar Arkhan</name></author><id>tag:yukiisbored.github.io,2017-04-13:/hello-again.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div id="preamble"&gt;
&lt;div class="sectionbody"&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello world, it&amp;#8217;s been a long time since I write something. Well, due to
a lot of constraints like school, work, and some other stuff. It&amp;#8217;s hard
to find a good time and mood to write something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;You probably noticed that the whole site change. In fact, it …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="preamble"&gt;
&lt;div class="sectionbody"&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello world, it&amp;#8217;s been a long time since I write something. Well, due to
a lot of constraints like school, work, and some other stuff. It&amp;#8217;s hard
to find a good time and mood to write something.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;You probably noticed that the whole site change. In fact, it&amp;#8217;s not just
the looks of it but the whole infrastructure and setup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I replaced Jekyll with Pelican due to a number of things:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="olist arabic"&gt;&lt;ol class="arabic"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It&amp;#8217;s complex to utilize
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It&amp;#8217;s confusing for most of the time
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
It mainly uses markdown
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sure, this is &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; opinionated but really this is just a tool that I
as the user uses to generate static pages and publish it on Github pages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main reason why I like Pelican more than Jekyll is simplicity of usage,
clear documentation, and extensibility. I just don&amp;#8217;t find Jekyll to be a
really nice tool for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not to mention that I can write in AsciiDoc instead of the absurd mess that
everyone loves, Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really don&amp;#8217;t like Markdown because of it&amp;#8217;s ambiguity and weird nature. It
was never made to be a good markup language. The main sole purpose of Markdown
is to be parsed to HTML and make it "easier" to write. It&amp;#8217;s not mainly made
to write papers, books, nor articles. Not to mention a lot of good stuff are
lacking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, I won&amp;#8217;t be signing my blog posts because I commonly lose my PGP keys.
Well, that&amp;#8217;s just bad on my part and I&amp;#8217;m looking a good way to utilize PGP
and pEp seems to be a good project making it easier for normal people to
use it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still, I&amp;#8217;m looking for a good way to backup my private keys encrypted. I find
keybase cloud encryption backup to be quite confusing because I can&amp;#8217;t find a
way to get the keys to my system by any means.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Actually, the main reason I don&amp;#8217;t want to sign my blog posts is because I can&amp;#8217;t
find a good way to embed it without having junk on the rendered document.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been working a lot on &lt;a href="https://solar.coala.io"&gt;solar&lt;/a&gt; lately and not much on
Loklak. Well, this is because I favor system administration work over programming.
I&amp;#8217;m not quite sure which one I should take because programming is starting to be
a more of a hobby thing for me. Sure, I still &lt;strong&gt;love&lt;/strong&gt; creating and writing free
software but I just love doing "DevOps"/sysadmin work more. This is probably
because I&amp;#8217;m heavily addicited to *nix systems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also built my own retro gaming machine with my Raspberry Pi 3 and it&amp;#8217;s really
awesome. I use RetroPie but not the image file because downloading it is too slow
to the point it just fails (smh github releases). So I ended up using raspbian and
install it manually. I can finally relax with Chrono Trigger and Castlevania &amp;lt;3.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just watched KonoSuba season 2 and it was funny as the first season. I find it
amusing how unique and charming the whole anime is and I&amp;#8217;m looking forward for
the next season. I also find it quite unique to parody SAO but with more quality
than it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a long time since I read Re:Life and I haven&amp;#8217;t read the new chapters
since February. Please don&amp;#8217;t mail me spoilers ;w;, I want to read it someday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also find it amusing that I can surpass to the province level at the type of
event that I really hate with a passion which is Competitive Programming. Yes,
I joined the local """Computer""" Olympiad which is CP with more cringy and
cancerous elitism. I find some of the contestants quite amusing and I promote
Google Code-In and Besut Kode to the other contestants to my suprise nobody
even heard of the program. There were a handful of people who heard about it
but didn&amp;#8217;t joined, I find it quite sad that the ministry of education promotes
total garbage that won&amp;#8217;t even be used in their carreer over an actual free
and open source software contributor kickstarter like GCI that would look
fucking gorgeous on the Resume/CV.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The goverment doesn&amp;#8217;t care by any means about Free and Open Source Software.
They&amp;#8217;ll use pirated copies of Windows, Office, and some other cancerous shites.
The ministry of education has failed to educate the people on ownership and
copyright because they&amp;#8217;re the ones who distributes pirated copies of Windows
Server 2012 to schools via VirtualBox Hard Drive images for their Computer based
National Exams program. I find it to be quite a bang to the head. It&amp;#8217;s ironic
where the president of Indonesia wants a war with pirated goods but his own
goverment keeps pirating Windows, Office, and a mountain of things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a tip &lt;strong&gt;promote free software&lt;/strong&gt; also &lt;strong&gt;free&lt;/strong&gt; as in &lt;strong&gt;free speech&lt;/strong&gt; not &lt;strong&gt;free beer&lt;/strong&gt;.
I believe free software can help the country to become better and more
transparent. Free software promotes diversity, collaboration, and teaches people.
Unlike non-free software where nobody can learn from it or improve it other than
the sole owner. Besides, I really don&amp;#8217;t like the fact pirated software are sold
publicly without any shame. It&amp;#8217;s like selling tobacco without regulations and
freely to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;And here I am building networks and servers for my school with solely free
software. Setup an awesome instance of Moodle for my school and setup the
students' wifi with pfSense and OpenWRT. It proved to be a reliable choice.
In fact, We did comparison with pfSense on a Modern Pentium Machine vs
Routerboard running MikroTik. pfSense proved to be more faster and lesser
latency than the expensive routerboard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why use non-free software and even worse pirating it, use &lt;strong&gt;free software&lt;/strong&gt; and
share it with your friends and neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Man, I sound like Richard Stallman all of the sudden. Even though I like how BSD
does things than GNU/Linux. Sorry, Stallman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a terribly long time since I write code in Go. I find it amusing
because it&amp;#8217;s my favorite language of all time. This is probably the fact the orgs
I mainly work with is using Java or Python and none of them uses Go daily.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m also becoming a GSoC mentor mostly for experiences and helping coala. I&amp;#8217;m
hoping I can still join GSoC, if not I&amp;#8217;ll probably do X.org EVOC instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Man, this is really turing out to be a really long post where I blab mostly about
what&amp;#8217;s going on lately. I should blog more often just to get stuff out of my chest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s this beauty in Emacs when you use it for writing. It&amp;#8217;s really really smooth
unlike anything. I don&amp;#8217;t like word processors like Microsoft Word, LibreOffice Writer,
etc. I just find them to be quite ambigious and find their shortcuts to be mundane.
I write faster with AsciiDoc on Emacs. That&amp;#8217;s just how it is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since I got this blazing new laptop, I can finally listen to music, write stuff, do
a mountain of other things while doing heavy load in the background like compiling.
This Lenovo Ideapad running i7 Kabylake is seriously too good to be true on this
price and it is. Sure, it has a really annoying problem because it uses realtek
wifi which is absolute crap on Linux but that&amp;#8217;s okay I guess I&amp;#8217;ll just buy a wifi
dongle that uses Atheros.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, GCI Experience post&amp;#8230; Yeah&amp;#8230; probably later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s about it, I guess.
Thanks for reading this really really long blab which I doubt anyone to be reading it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="stories"></category><category term="opinions"></category></entry><entry><title>Backend Voodoo Magic</title><link href="https://yukiisbored.github.io/backend-voodoo-magic.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-17T16:22:00+07:00</published><updated>2017-02-17T16:22:00+07:00</updated><author><name>Muhammad Kaisar Arkhan</name></author><id>tag:yukiisbored.github.io,2017-02-17:/backend-voodoo-magic.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div id="preamble"&gt;
&lt;div class="sectionbody"&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;So coala has a new website and it’s lovely and moe (props to
&lt;a href="https://github.com/hemangsk"&gt;@hemangsk&lt;/a&gt; for making such a beautiful
site) but it has one particular problem. The backend which is used to
fetch contributors and make the fancy &amp;#8220;Try coala&amp;#8221; feature to work goes
502 on a regular basis …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="preamble"&gt;
&lt;div class="sectionbody"&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;So coala has a new website and it’s lovely and moe (props to
&lt;a href="https://github.com/hemangsk"&gt;@hemangsk&lt;/a&gt; for making such a beautiful
site) but it has one particular problem. The backend which is used to
fetch contributors and make the fancy &amp;#8220;Try coala&amp;#8221; feature to work goes
502 on a regular basis. Which is pretty bad and really annoying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;At first, I just restarted it and hope it won’t do that again, but after
a couple of hours it goes 502 again, at this point, I might as well as
try to invoke it locally and &lt;span class="monospaced"&gt;curl&lt;/span&gt; says there’s no reply. I run bash
inside the container and &lt;span class="monospaced"&gt;curl&lt;/span&gt; it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I looked at the logs and it’s empty. The program didn’t output anything
and I try to find some sort of log files but I have no idea where it is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I asked &lt;a href="https://github.com/hemangsk"&gt;@hemangsk&lt;/a&gt; for the reason why the
logs are empty. It turns out Django doesn’t output logs because it’s
&amp;#8220;production&amp;#8221;. Which is pretty bad IMVHO, because it makes problems on
production really hard to bug and it makes it even harder to debug a new
bug on production.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I ran the backend on my machine with &amp;#8220;development&amp;#8221; mode and it
just freezes. I asked the community team why it’s freezing for some
reason and &lt;a href="https://github.com/sils"&gt;@sils&lt;/a&gt; said to wait for it fetching contributors data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;After a couple of hours, this is already taking too much time.
&lt;a href="https://github.com/sils"&gt;@sils&lt;/a&gt; told &lt;a href="https://github.com/h"&gt;hemangsk&lt;/a&gt; to include
a loaded database to the repository. So, I pulled the new docker image,
recreate the container, and start it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;After another couple of hours, it goes to the dreaded 502 error again. I
asked the community team if it’s fetching contributors on another
thread. &lt;a href="https://github.com/sils"&gt;@sils&lt;/a&gt; told me it’s on a &lt;em&gt;cronjob&lt;/em&gt;. I looked at the
&lt;span class="monospaced"&gt;settings.py&lt;/span&gt; file and it’s there. after a couple of minutes,
&lt;a href="https://github.com/sils"&gt;@sils&lt;/a&gt; and I noticed we’re using Django’s development server
instead of a proper Python WSGI HTTP server like Gunicorn or uWSGI.
&lt;a href="https://github.com/sils"&gt;@sils&lt;/a&gt; suggested uWSGI but I told him to use Gunicorn because of
from my experience it’s pretty fast and the advantage of having multiple
workers. In the end, we used gunicorn and it’s stable for a whole week
which is an outstanding achievement from the usual 6 hours of uptime.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;To make sure it works for a really long time (long enough for me to
watch an entire series and movies of Evangelion), I scaled the container
for it, used haproxy as a load balancer using the classic round-robin
and everything went buttery smooth!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I start to like Docker even more especially with making scaling stuff
really easy and simple. Sure, it has a couple of problems like Docker
engine touching your iptables and create forward rules that you didn’t
notice but really those are manageable and it’s not like it has some
unsecure default like MongoDB.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I haven’t touched Kubernetes and I hope I can play with it in the
future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s all, Kaisar Arkhan (Yuki) &amp;lt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;P.S: I have to apologize. The &amp;#8220;My GCI Experience&amp;#8221; story have to be
delayed because I’m currently not in my writing mood and I’ve been
pretty busy with school stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="system administration"></category><category term="docker"></category><category term="python"></category></entry><entry><title>Hello World</title><link href="https://yukiisbored.github.io/hello-world.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-02-02T12:03:00+07:00</published><updated>2017-02-02T12:03:00+07:00</updated><author><name>Muhammad Kaisar Arkhan</name></author><id>tag:yukiisbored.github.io,2017-02-02:/hello-world.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div id="preamble"&gt;
&lt;div class="sectionbody"&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello World, because of popular demand, I&amp;#8217;m starting a new blog powered by Jekyll
and GitHub pages. In the future, I&amp;#8217;ll probably post semi-serious or random stuff
in this webpage. My upcoming post will be my 1.5 month experience participating
in Google Code-in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m planning …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;div id="preamble"&gt;
&lt;div class="sectionbody"&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello World, because of popular demand, I&amp;#8217;m starting a new blog powered by Jekyll
and GitHub pages. In the future, I&amp;#8217;ll probably post semi-serious or random stuff
in this webpage. My upcoming post will be my 1.5 month experience participating
in Google Code-in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m planning to "prettify" this website as much as I can (if you know enough, you
can see I&amp;#8217;m not good at design or drawing).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;#8217;t know me, I just want to say Hello, nice to meet you &amp;lt;3. My name is
Muhammad Kaisar Arkhan or commonly known under the alias yuki\_is\_bored. I&amp;#8217;m
just your average, \*nix system adminstrator and programmer. I usually do it when
"I have the time", because I&amp;#8217;m currently still in my second year of High School.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;#8217;ve became the grand prize winner GCI 2016 under the FOSSASIA org, but
more detail for that later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;English is not my native language so expect some nasty grammer mistakes, if you
notice some, please tell me via &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/yuki_is_bored"&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt; or
&lt;a href="mailto:yukinagato@protonmail.com"&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt; because I want to improve my writing
skills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;That is all,
Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="paragraph"&gt;&lt;p&gt;P.S: All of my posts will always be signed under my [Keybase account][keybase]
as a detached &lt;span class="monospaced"&gt;.sign&lt;/span&gt; file inside the &lt;span class="monospaced"&gt;_signs&lt;/span&gt; folder on the [repo][repo].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content><category term="greetings"></category><category term="blab"></category></entry></feed>